<resources>
    <string name="app_name">SemestralnaPracaDoom</string>
    <string name="lore_2">Their journey leads them deeper into the heart of the invasion, where they encounter the main source of the demonic threat. Armed and determined, they confront the most powerful demon in a bid to stop the apocalypse and save humanity.</string>
    <string name="lore_3">Through relentless combat and strategic prowess, the marine battles through the depths of hell, facing increasingly daunting challenges until they confront the ultimate evil threatening to consume both Mars and Earth.</string>
    <string name="lore_1">In the year 1993, at a space research facility on Mars, a gateway to hell was opened, unleashing a horde of demons. The player assumes the role of a marine soldier, who becomes humanity\'s last hope. Venturing through the research complex, the player confronts an army of demons and fights for survival. Armed with various weapons and tactics, they navigate through bloody corridors, battling against the endless stream of infernal forces.</string>
    <string name="idSoftware_title">ID Software</string>
    <string name="idSoftware_P1_title">The Beginnings of id Software</string>
    <string name="idSoftware_P1_body">id Software was founded in February 1991 by four key individuals: John Carmack, John Romero, Tom Hall, and Adrian Carmack. The team initially worked at a company called Softdisk, where they created games for the PC and Apple II platforms. However, they had bigger ambitions and wanted to develop their own games independently.</string>
    <string name="idSoftware_P2_body">The breakthrough came when John Carmack developed a revolutionary technique for smooth-scrolling graphics on the PC. This technique was showcased in their first game, Commander Keen, which they developed in their spare time while still employed at Softdisk. The game was a huge success, proving that the team had the talent and vision to make it on their own.</string>
    <string name="idSoftware_P3_body">Encouraged by the success of Commander Keen, the team left Softdisk and officially founded id Software. They quickly established themselves as pioneers in the gaming industry, creating groundbreaking titles such as Wolfenstein 3D, Doom, and Quake. These games not only set new standards for graphics and gameplay but also laid the foundation for the first-person shooter genre.</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_title">Interesting Facts</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P1_title">Pioneer in 3D Graphics:</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P1_body">Doom is often regarded as one of the first games to feature true 3D graphics. Although the game uses a technique known as \"2.5D\" (first-person perspective with 2D sprites), its speed and fluidity were revolutionary at the time.</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P2_title">Multiplayer and Modding:</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P2_body">Doom was one of the first games to enable players to play together over a network, laying the foundation for modern multiplayer gaming. Additionally, the game supported modding, allowing players to create their own levels and modifications. This led to the emergence of a massive modding community that remains active to this day.</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P3_title">Impact on the Gaming Industry:</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P3_body">Doom had a tremendous impact on the gaming industry and helped popularize the FPS (first-person shooter) genre. Its success inspired numerous other games and contributed to the development of modern first-person shooters.</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P4_title">Controversy and Censorship:</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P4_body">Doom became a target of controversy due to its violent and satanic themes. The game was banned or censored in some countries. Despite this, it became a cult classic and its popularity remained unaffected.</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P5_title">Birth of id Software</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P5_body">Doom was developed by id Software, founded by John Carmack and John Romero. The game cemented their reputation as pioneers in game development and led to the release of other successful titles like Quake and Wolfenstein 3D.</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P6_title">Technical Innovations:</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P6_body">Doom introduced several technical innovations, such as BSP (Binary Space Partitioning) for efficient level rendering, and advanced lighting and shading techniques for its time.</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P7_title">Pop Culture References:</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P7_body">The game contains numerous references to pop culture, including sci-fi movies and books. Its iconic weapons, enemies, and sound effects have become entrenched in pop culture lexicon.</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P8_title">Music:</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P8_body">The game\'s soundtrack, composed by Robert Prince, was heavily influenced by heavy metal bands like Metallica and Slayer. The music added to the game\'s atmosphere and is still appreciated by fans today.</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P9_title">Speedrunning and Community:</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P9_body">Doom became one of the first games to support speedrunning – playing the game with the goal of completing it as quickly as possible. The speedrunning community is very active, with regular competitions and events.</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P10_title">Anniversaries and Remakes:</string>
    <string name="interestingFacts_P10_body">The game has seen several remakes and ports to various platforms. On the occasion of the game\'s 25th anniversary, special editions and events were held to celebrate its legacy.</string>
    <string name="BackButton_text">Back!</string>
    <string name="lore_title">Lore Of DOOM</string>
    <string name="lore_EP1">Knee-Deep in the Dead</string>
    <string name="lore_EP1_lvl1">Hangar</string>
    <string name="lore_EP1_lvl2">Nuclear Plant</string>
    <string name="lore_EP1_lvl3">Toxin Refinery</string>
    <string name="lore_EP1_lvl4">Command Control</string>
    <string name="lore_EP1_lvl5">Phobos Lab</string>
    <string name="lore_EP1_lvl6">Central Processing</string>
    <string name="lore_EP1_lvl7">Computer Station</string>
    <string name="lore_EP1_lvl8">Phobos Anomaly</string>
    <string name="lore_EP2_title">The Shores of Hell</string>
    <string name="lore_EP2_lvl1">Deimos Anomaly</string>
    <string name="lore_EP2_lvl2">Containment Area</string>
    <string name="lore_EP2_lvl3">Refinery</string>
    <string name="lore_EP2_lvl4">Deimos Lab</string>
    <string name="lore_EP2_lvl5">Command Center</string>
    <string name="lore_EP2_lvl6">Halls of the Damned</string>
    <string name="lore_EP2_lvl7">Spawning Vats</string>
    <string name="lore_EP2_lvl8">Tower of Babel</string>
    <string name="lore_EP3_title">Inferno</string>
    <string name="lore_EP3_lvl1">Hell Keep</string>
    <string name="lore_EP3_lvl2">Slough of Despair</string>
    <string name="lore_EP3_lvl3">Pandemonium</string>
    <string name="lore_EP3_lvl4">House of Pain</string>
    <string name="lore_EP3_lvl5">Unholy Cathedral</string>
    <string name="lore_EP3_lvl6">Mt. Erebus</string>
    <string name="lore_EP3_lvl7">Limbo</string>
    <string name="lore_EP3_lvl8">Dis</string>
    <string name="menu_myPlay">MY PLAY</string>
    <string name="menu_lore">LORE</string>
    <string name="menu_monsters">MONSTERS</string>
    <string name="menu_idSoftware">ID SOFTWARE</string>
    <string name="menu_interestingFacts">INTERESTING FACTS</string>
    <string name="menu_quiz">QUIZ</string>
    <string name="monsters_title">Monsters</string>
    <string name="myPlayNotes_title">All notes</string>
    <string name="myPlay_title">My Play</string>
    <string name="myPlay_currentlyOn">"Currently on: "</string>
    <string name="myPlay_finishLevel">Finish Level!</string>
    <string name="myPlay_notes">Notes:</string>
    <string name="myPlay_allNotes">All notes</string>
    <string name="quiz_endOfQuiz">End of Quiz</string>
    <string name="quiz_playAgain">Play Again</string>
    <string name="quiz_title">Quiz</string>
</resources>